Priyanka Saggu

About

Summary

Resourceful DevOps enthusiast with experience in networking and programming. As a summer trainee at Dgplug, have set up and managed multiple Linux servers. Wrote Infrastructure as Code(IaC) to automate setting up of tightly-secured and SSH-hardened systems/servers and On-Prem deployment environments. Working closely under the guidance of mentors from leading upstream open-source projects. And currently an Outreachy'19 intern at GNOME Foundation.

Personal Info

- Email: priyankasaggu11929@gmail.com
- Website: https://priyankasaggu11929.github.io/
- Gitlab-gnome: https://gitlab.gnome.org/priyankasaggu119
- Gitlab-salsa: https://salsa.debian.org/priyankasaggu119-guest
- Github: https://github.com/Priyankasaggu11929/
- · Resume.pdf: download here

Experience

Community Learning & Contributions

Dgplug Summer Training

2018-Present

- Set up and managed multiple Linux distribution servers.
- Wrote Ansible scripts to automatically update system components and setup production environments.
- Set up a WriteFreely multi-user instance behind reverse-proxy.
- Set up multiple Docker containers, orchestrated using Docker Swarm, for carrying out test deployments.
- Wrote Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to setup SSH-hardened servers.
- Contributed to **lymworkbook** a **Vagrant lab environment** in setting up a few basic level sys-admins problems.
- Setup OpenVpn service, creating both OpenVPN server and Certificate Authority (CA) server on different machines.
- Setup On-Prem multi-cluster orchestriation platform for microservices applications deployment using kubernetes tools.

Debian

2019

- Packaged 4 django/flask dependency python modules under Debian-Python-Modules-Team (DPMT).
- Packaged and updated 5+ ruby-gems for Debian-Diaspora project under Debian-Ruby-Team (DRT).
- Contributed to the Debian-gitlab project under Debian-javascript-team (DJT). Improved old node modules, packaged new ones and was constantly involved in testing of Debian-gitlab for then-stable version release.

Gnome - gtranslator

2019-Present

- Enhanced UI by revamping existing widgets in accordance with Gnome Human Interface Guidelines(HIG).
- Redesigned existing search-and-replace-bar to a new libdazzle style popover overlay widget.
- Currently working as an Outreachy Intern under the project.

Internships

GNOME Foundation

Outreachy'19 Intern - Present

• Learn IT, Girl (Certificate)

Scholar mentee - 2019

• GeeksforGeeks, Noida (Certificate)

Graphics designer intern - 2018

Skills/ Keywords

- Linux: Debian family (Ubuntu, Debian Buster), Red Hat family (CentOS)
- Scripting: Bash and utils, Python
- Backend: Python (Django)
- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript (JQuery, PhaserJS)
- GUI Toolkit: GTK+ 3 in pure C
- Databases: MySQL, SQLite
- Web Application servers/proxies: Nginx, Apache2
- Version control systems: Git
- **DevOps**: Kubernetes, Rancher, Ansible, Docker, Docker Swarm, Helm/Helm Charts, Prometheus & Grafana, Velero, Weave Cloud, Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), RabbitMQ
- Misc: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), OpenCV, Java-J2SE

Education

B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering

Deenbandhu Chhotu Ram University of Science & Technology, Murthal (Sonepat), Haryana 2015-2019

• AISSCE (12th-PCM)

Govt. Model Senior Secondary School, Sector 35-D, Chandigarh (U.T.) 2014-2015

• AISSE (10th)

S.B.P. D.A.V Centenary Public School, Fatehabad, Haryana 2012-2013

Conferences/ Events

- 2019 PyCon, India
- 2019 DebUtsav, Delhi
- 2017 International Conference on Textile Advances-TAI India

Additional activities

- Regional Head Haryana, GirlScript Foundation Private Limited.
- Organised Python 101 BootCamp in Haryana state-level technical fest, Technova.
- Attended IWD'19 event in Google, Gurugram. Also, the women's mega day meetup in Microsoft, Gurugram.

Writings

Self

- Parse Server On-Premise Deployment
- A guide to a "safer" SSH!
- Consul Key-Value Store!
- Let's get started with iptables!
- Automating WordPress Installation Through Ansible!
- Setting up WriteFreely multi-user instance in production!

Publications

- Introduction to Xamarin | A Software for Mobile App Development and App Creation
- Flutter | An Introduction to the Open Source SDK by Google

References

• Chandan Kumar, OpenStack/RDO developer, Red Hat, chkumar AT redhat DOT com